<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tils on @ozgurvurgun</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/</link><description>Recent content in Tils on @ozgurvurgun</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>ozgurvurgun</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 06:06:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#15</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 06:06:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/15/</guid><description>Pubky is a collection of opensource protocols and tools to keep web unstoppable
Official web site: https://pubky.org/</description></item><item><title>#14</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/14/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 18:21:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/14/</guid><description/></item><item><title>#13</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/13/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 13:08:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/13/</guid><description>I realized there is visibilitychange event in web api when I enter instagram on pc, and the instagram stops playin reels when i go to another tab. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that event exists. You can know the tab is visible or hidden with that. mozmdn-visibilitychange</description></item><item><title>#12</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 14:59:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/12/</guid><description>Borekitas / Empanada Ispanya&amp;rsquo;dan gocen seferadlarin mutfagina ait bir lezzet. Ladinolar Empanada&amp;rsquo;yi Borekitas olarak cevirmisler, bu da borekcik demekmis. Empanada farkili cesitlerde olabiliyor ama borekitas sadece patates ve patlicandan yapilirmis. 185 derece firinda alt-ust fanli olacak sekilde aciyoruz.
Onemli noktalar:
patlicanlar kozlenecek ama cekirdeksiz olacak mutlaka aycicek yagi ve oda sicakliginda su +4 derece olacak italyanlar limon ispanyollar sirke kullaniyor, beyaz sarap sirkesi daha iyi oluyor. un mutlaka elenmeli, yavas yavas eklenmeli, ekmek unu kullanilmali.</description></item><item><title>#11</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 21:19:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/11/</guid><description>I recently decided to give the Zed editor a try. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Vim for years (and Linux-as-an-IDE), but Zed caught my eye with its modern features, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d check it out.
Everything about Zed seems great, and I honestly think it&amp;rsquo;s one of the best editors out there. However, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t shake the feeling of something being off, even when using Vim mode. Now I understand why they mention it&amp;rsquo;s 90% compatible with Vim.</description></item><item><title>#10</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 21:10:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/10/</guid><description>Adding Soft-Delete in PostgreSQL Without Changing Code I recently needed to add a soft-delete feature to my application. However, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to modify the existing program code. Instead, I leveraged PostgreSQL&amp;rsquo;s rule system to achieve this. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I did it:
I created a migration that automatically logs deleted rows into a separate table whenever a DELETE statement is executed. This ensures the original data is preserved.
CREATE TABLE deleted_data ( id SERIAL PRIMARY KEY, table_name TEXT NOT NULL, row_data JSONB NOT NULL, deleted_at TIMESTAMP DEFAULT CURRENT_TIMESTAMP ); CREATE RULE log_course_deletion AS ON DELETE TO course DO ALSO INSERT INTO deleted_data (table_name, row_data) VALUES (&amp;#39;course&amp;#39;, row_to_json(OLD)); With this setup, every time a row is deleted from the course table, it is automatically inserted into the deleted_data table.</description></item><item><title>#09</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/09/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 10:59:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/09/</guid><description>Today I saw utteranc.es in a blog and i liked it. So I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to add same comment to my blog. Replaced with disqus (which already its not working). You can see comment for below of the every post. You need to login with your github account if you want to write comments.</description></item><item><title>#08</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/08/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 11:03:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/08/</guid><description>Julian Day or Julian Day Number (JDN) is a date format. Its the number of days that have passed since 1 January 4713 BC in Julian Calendar
And my birthday in that format is 2447579</description></item><item><title>#07</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/07/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 08:41:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/07/</guid><description>I am not fan o em unit to give sizes to html content. But unfortunately I have to work with other developers sometimes. So, some of those likes to use em unit but they have no idea how the em works. Yes I don&amp;rsquo;t have idea until today. So I have to learn the calculation of em.
Let me share with you too.
EM is relative unit to the nearest parent font-size.</description></item><item><title>#06</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 17:38:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/06/</guid><description>Today I learned how can i create a rust cli application with help of ai.
I&amp;rsquo;ve created this tool for managing TIL records. Now I can add more til&amp;rsquo;s without worring to creating new file and committing etc.
https://github.com/delirehberi/tiller
I am very happy about it :)</description></item><item><title>#05</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/05/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/05/</guid><description>Point-free Programming / Tacit Programming
Bu konuda yeterince ingilizce içerik var zaten. Türkçe olarak açıklarsam fonksiyonu tanımlarken alacağı parametreyi belirtmediğinizde point-free programlama yapıyorsunuz. Buradaki point kelimesi &amp;ldquo;.&amp;rdquo; manasında değil. Aksine bolca &amp;ldquo;.&amp;rdquo; operatörü ile birleştirme yapılabilmesi için de çok güzel oluyor. Çok nokta görünüyor yani bu tarzda.
birekle :: Int -&amp;gt; Int birekle sayi = sayi + 1 birekle = (+) 1 --pointfree Okunabilirlik konusunda ise &amp;ldquo;okunabilirlik aşinalıktır&amp;rdquo; lafına bakarsak bu tarzı benimsediğinizde daha okunabilir bir tarz oluyor.</description></item><item><title>#04</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/04/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/04/</guid><description>Zero Knowledge Proof
There is a way to get proof for &amp;ldquo;thing&amp;rdquo; without getting any &amp;ldquo;sensitive&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;private&amp;rdquo; information from.
Zero Knowledge Proof
BUT for now its to expensive to implement for tiny projects. Calculations requires a lot costs.</description></item><item><title>#02</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/02/</guid><description>There is tool named bgrem for using image models to remove backgrounds
pipenv shell pipenv install bgrem[cli] bgrem i file.jpg output-file.jpg i argument for specifing input file
s argument runs a server and web-ui on port 5000 to use models.
First usage of model requires download. So it will take a little bit time to complete at first run of model.</description></item><item><title>#03</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/03/</guid><description>Yarn issue
Error: tunneling socket could not be established, statusCode=400 Cause: Proxy config in yarn Solution:
yarn config delete https-proxy yarn config delete proxy</description></item><item><title>#01</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 13:14:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/til/01/</guid><description>To create custom content types just create a new folder inside content folder.
Started Today I Learned contents.</description></item></channel></rss>