<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English on emre.xyz | @delirehberi</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/categories/english/</link><description>Recent content in English on emre.xyz | @delirehberi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>delirehberi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/categories/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What makes a language good for me?</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/what-makes-a-language-good-for-me/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/what-makes-a-language-good-for-me/</guid><description>&lt;p>In short: &lt;strong>Syntax&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I believe that humans evolved through language. All human languages are amazing because they allow us to express ourselves and our needs with high correctness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>No How, Live Long What! - Experiences with AI Tools on Software Development</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/no-how-live-long-what-ai-tools-in-software-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/no-how-live-long-what-ai-tools-in-software-development/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Copilot + ChatGPT for my daily development work for the last six months, and it has significantly accelerated my productivity. This new workflow has transformed my development journey, removing the stress of figuring out how to do things. Now, I just focus on what needs to be done.
Let me explain.
Before adopting this workflow, I used various languages to accomplish my tasks: PHP and Node.js for web development, and Go and Python for backend or CLI app development.</description></item><item><title>What is emoji?</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/what-is-emoji/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/what-is-emoji/</guid><description>I read a blog post about the history of emojis. The article was full of details and descriptions. The author didn&amp;rsquo;t give a strict definition of what emojis are and suggested that everyone can have their own idea about them.
After thinking about it, I came up with my own definition.
To me, emojis are like emotional signs that we use in communication alongside letters. This definition excludes other types of visual languages, like hieroglyphics, which are pictures or symbols representing words.</description></item></channel></rss>