<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>art on emre.xyz | @delirehberi</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/tags/art/</link><description>Recent content in art on emre.xyz | @delirehberi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>delirehberi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fikret Mualla: Sanat ve Melankoli Üzerine Bir Portre</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/fikret-mualla/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/fikret-mualla/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fikret Mualla cumhuriyet dönemi ressamlarından ve kendi tarzını bulabilmiş müthiş bir ressam olsa da hayatı çoğunlukla sorunlu geçmiş birisi. Picasso&amp;rsquo;nun hediye ettiği resmi dahi hiç parasına satacak kadar umursamaz bir insan olan Mualla&amp;rsquo;nın resimler günümüzde oldukça değerli. Fikret Mualla&amp;rsquo;yı bu kadar değerli yapan ilginç hayatına kısa bir göz atacağım.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kaynak olarak çoğunlukla Hıfzı Topuz&amp;rsquo;un eserlerinden faydalandım.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>İyi okumalar.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Artful Journey of Gülsüm Sayım: A Deep Dive into Her World of Paintings</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/gulsum-sayim-painter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/gulsum-sayim-painter/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello friends. A lot of you already know me as Software Developer for a long time. But less knows I started to study Art Of History in 2021. I am so excited to share my first article about a painter. She is a very talented painter and also She is my cousin. I want to thank her to answer my boring questions with patience and brilliant anwsers. I followed a simple way to complete this interview. First I&amp;rsquo;ve created my basic questions and separate by sections. Then I&amp;rsquo;ve add more detailed questions to each section. I&amp;rsquo;ve asked her to answer these questions. After that I&amp;rsquo;ve combined her answers and created this article. I belive you will enjoy it. I know a lot will like these beautiful paintings. I will share her social media accounts at the end of the article. You can follow her to see more of her beautiful paintings.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>