<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>en on emre.xyz | @delirehberi</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/tags/en/</link><description>Recent content in en on emre.xyz | @delirehberi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>delirehberi</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/tags/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Artful Journey of Gülsüm Sayım: A Deep Dive into Her World of Paintings</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/gulsum-sayim-painter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/gulsum-sayim-painter/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello friends. A lot of you already know me as Software Developer for a long time. But less knows I started to study Art Of History in 2021. I am so excited to share my first article about a painter. She is a very talented painter and also She is my cousin. I want to thank her to answer my boring questions with patience and brilliant anwsers. I followed a simple way to complete this interview. First I&amp;rsquo;ve created my basic questions and separate by sections. Then I&amp;rsquo;ve add more detailed questions to each section. I&amp;rsquo;ve asked her to answer these questions. After that I&amp;rsquo;ve combined her answers and created this article. I belive you will enjoy it. I know a lot will like these beautiful paintings. I will share her social media accounts at the end of the article. You can follow her to see more of her beautiful paintings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Disabling Screen Off and Screensaver on Debian / Linux</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/linux-disable-screen-off-and-screensaver/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/linux-disable-screen-off-and-screensaver/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re using a Linux system and want to prevent your screen from turning off or your screensaver from activating, you can use the &lt;code>xset&lt;/code> command to adjust your Display Power Management Signaling (DPMS) settings and screensaver settings. Here’s how you can do it:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A journey with beeper the all in one messaging app</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/a-journey-with-beeper-the-all-in-one-messaging-app/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/a-journey-with-beeper-the-all-in-one-messaging-app/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, I embarked on a journey with &lt;a href="https://www.beeper.com/">Beeper&lt;/a>, an app that promises to unify all your messaging applications into one. The idea of having a single hub for all my conversations was intriguing, and I was eager to see how it would pan out. Here are my thoughts after a few weeks of using Beeper.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-promise-of-unity">The Promise of Unity&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The concept of Beeper, a one-stop-shop for all messaging apps, is a compelling one. However, as I realized(finally lol), each messaging app has its unique features that make it special. Translating these unique features into a single app is a Herculean task, and it&amp;rsquo;s understandable if some features get lost in translation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using postgresql in non daemon way</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/using-postgresql-in-non-daemon-way/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/using-postgresql-in-non-daemon-way/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a preference against installing servers locally and running them as systemd services, which is why I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of Docker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, there are times when I simply want to use servers as specific apps, without having to go through a system-wide installation, even with docker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take #postgresql as an example. A typical installation creates a user, installs files in your root directories, changes ownerships, creates service files, and so on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Do everyone needs slack or other ims</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/do-everyone-needs-slack-or-other-ims/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/do-everyone-needs-slack-or-other-ims/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="tldr-no-of-course-not">tldr; NO!, of course not!&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The first question is what is the problem which trying to be solved by IMs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I believe that the problem is connectivity. So clear enough. All IM brands are tries to solve connection problem between people. People wants to reach each other whenever they want. This is all about &amp;ldquo;EVOLUTION&amp;rdquo;, ehe, ehe, ehe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What i want</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/what-i-want/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/what-i-want/</guid><description>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t write a post in English for a long time. You know, easy to write in my mother-language of course, but i can not to improve my language skills if i don&amp;rsquo;t write. This is an important thing to making progress in language learning.
I&amp;rsquo;m in a path nowadays. Am i need to stay in my country or am i need to move to another place.
I&amp;rsquo;m a kind of nationalist and in my heart, believe me, i want to stay in here.</description></item><item><title>Searching with the power of postgresql in symfony applications</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/searching-with-the-power-of-postgresql-in-symfony-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/searching-with-the-power-of-postgresql-in-symfony-applications/</guid><description>&lt;p>For instance, you need to write a search page for your last project, and it is not big enough to use an external search engine. Still, you want to use some powerful text searching features. You are brilliant if you preferred PostgreSQL as your database. Because PostgreSQL has very, very powerful search capabilities. I want to share some of them with you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My morning routine</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/my-morning-routine/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/my-morning-routine/</guid><description>Hi, kats;
I want to talk about my morning routine. I try to keep this routine for 5 weeks and I want to stuck with this routine.
I wake up at approximately 06:00 am every morning. I try to be as consistent as possible with this because it helps I stay motivated.
Once I&amp;rsquo;m up, the first thing I do is wash my face and I feed my cats (Tedi and Turgut).</description></item><item><title>Hello world</title><link>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ozgurvurgun.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>This is my blog&amp;rsquo;s new face. I&amp;rsquo;ll write my posts here after this.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think to move my old posts to this blog. You can view my posts from github archive if you need it.
Sometimes I may write posts in Turkish, sometimes in English. It would be practice for me I think.
I plan to write a post once in three days.
Anyway, hello world posts should be short.</description></item></channel></rss>